RANDALL J. ZAK

5520 Miller Road Brecksville, Ohio 44141 (440) 526-5202

E-mail: raz2224@yahoo.com

SUMMARY

Managerial and technical data processing experience that includes strategic planning, business process and design, project management, systems methodology, structured systems analysis and design, product development, enterprise architecture and data warehousing, programming, software selection/evaluation, vendor relations and production support.

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration

Baldwin Wallace College Berea, Ohio

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Ohio State University Columbus, Ohio

EXPERIENCE

Independent Consultant

October 2008 - Present

Working with large Fortune 100 companies including Walmart, Target and Verizon on improving their affiliate marketing, SEO, and search strategies. Increased their online brand presence and grew online affiliate sales in excess of \$15 million dollars for fiscal year 2010.

Volunteered to help two non-for-profit organizations set up websites for their members to share information, post news, activities and other pertinent information.

Mirifex Consulting National City Bank Strongsville, Ohio April 2005 to October 2008

Data Warehouse Senior Project Manager

March 2008 - October 2008

Project manager responsible for integrating company wide data subject areas into the centralized data warehouse. Focus was on Argo/Connections, customer profiling and pipeline activities to better understand the banks customers and to develop a pipeline (sales cycle) to cross-sell banking products to customers.

Coordinated with the different resources to implement an iterative approach for each data warehousing project. Resources consisted of Subject Matter Experts, Business Analysts, Data Analysts, Data Architects, DBAs, ETL Developers, Quality Assurance Testers and Implementation Specialists.

Online Banking Senior Project Manager - Merger and Acquisitions

March 2006 - March 2008

MidAmerica Bank May 2007 – March 2008

Harbor and Fidelity Banks September 2006 – April 2007

Pioneer Bank March 2006 – August 2006

Partnered with the National City Electronic Banking LOB to define the requirements in order to convert the acquired bank's Online Banking data and Bill Payment data to National City Consumer and Small Business Online Banking system. Built and Managed a detailed work plan and project budget utilizing MS Project and Clarity as well as executive reporting and risk management. Project team consisted of 50+ resources in a Matrix environment with budgets of 1+ million dollars. Managed project team of primarily remote employees located throughout the United States.

Developed a reusable data transformation strategy, quality assurance testing and implementation process that was used for future acquisitions streamlining the timeline for conversions.

Provided conversion and balancing reports to ensure quality conversions. Provided reports to identify potential customer impacts because of functionality differences in the acquired bank's systems and that of National City.

Managed Argo/Connections release changes to make enhancements for the acquired bank to go live in Argo. Branch changes, Routing Transit Number changes, Control Classes etc.. were built into the Argo release schedule to coordinate with the "Go Live" date for Online Banking.

Project Manager

April 2005 - March 2007

Project Manager responsible for \$1 million plus project leading 50 plus resources in a matrix organization. The application is a four-tiered distributed application responsible for wire transfers in the banking industry. Integration of existing internal applications as well as integration with an external 3rd party application.

Responsible for the project budget and timeline utilizing MS Project and Clarity as well as executive reporting. Resources from all areas of the bank were involved in the design, development and security requirements providing a best in class project team.

The technical environment is comprised of WebSphere/JAVA utilizing an Oracle database. Protocols and transactions such as SOAP, https and LDAP are utilized in the sophisticated four-tiered environment.

Created and managed the requirements specification document, functional requirements, project plan as well as re-engineered the workflow process, using Visio and various In-House templates, across all phases of the project, which eliminated unnecessary steps and creating a

smother flow of data. The expectations of the Line-Of-Business were met to provide a seamless transition to the clients from the legacy platform to the Global Wire Transfer platform.

Hudson Global Solutions Consulting International Steel Group

Cleveland, Ohio November 2004 to April 2005

Senior Consultant and Team Leader

Team leader for the Operational Reporting datawarehouse environment. Responsible for team utilization, project charters and accountability for the production reporting environment. Responsible for five direct reports involving resource allocation and career development.

The datawarehousing environment was on a SQL Server 2000 platform utilizing DTS and trigger based processing for ETL data flow. Information was downloaded from multiple plant locations utilizing a manufacturing ERP system. The replication was near real time utilizing Progress triggers and a custom built ETL interface.

Established process controls consisting of quality checks, support and maintenance schedules and over all performance metrics and SLA's.

Insurance.com – Online Insurance

Cleveland, Ohio November 2000 to August 2004

IT Database Development Director

Responsible for relationship management with our financial and insurance partners including identifying user and business requirements, creating business and project plans and communicating and translating the high level business requirements to our technical IT departments. Created a process for production elevations and change management controls in terms of IT product releases. Project Manager for key projects utilizing MS Project and held accountable for budget requirements, resource allocation and time estimates. Financial partners include Fidelity, Bank One, National City, Capital One, Liberty Mutual, The Hartford Group, Travelers/Citgroup and more.

Responsible for the enterprise architecture and all database integration and information reporting activities within the organization managing a staff of IT resources. Responsible for hiring, performance evaluations and career development for five direct reports – two DBA's, two reporting analyst and one developer.

Installed and implemented from the ground up a SQL Server 2000 environment on a CX500 EMC Clariion disk array subsystem. Established backup and recovery plans, performance monitoring and a database change management processes for a 24x7 OLTP database. Responsible for database design, data warehousing, enterprise OLAP reporting and product development.

Production Environments include an OLTP run time database for our core product, a reporting data warehouse for external partners and a Microsoft OLAP management-reporting environment. Data modeling was done utilizing the Erwin modeling tool. Created logical

model from scratch to capture all necessary business requirements and created physical database model for OLAP and Data Warehouse for reporting. Utilized SQL Server's ETL tool DTS (Data Transformation Services) for mapping and transforming data from our OLTP database to our data warehouse and OLAP cubes. Put processes and controls in place for quality assurance of data and change management.

Responsible for developing and implementing a call center from the ground up. Performed detailed vendor analysis and due diligence in the software and hardware selection criteria and led the implementation effort of a \$1 million call center. Led the integration efforts in integrating the new call center data model into our enterprise model allowing for quality controls and enterprise reporting as well as supporting a call center incentive compensation program.

Coordinated integration between partner sites in terms of data transfer between our organization and the insurance carriers (JAVA, XML and IVANS formats). Led effort in installing online credit pulling in real time fashion. Negotiated contracts with Transunion and the associated carriers in utilizing the standard assist credit score in the underwriting process distributing credit costs across partners providing a win-win cost model. Strong knowledge of insurance industry, regulations, guidelines, credit modeling, MVR/CLUE, underwriting and risk tiering.

Responsible for all external reporting out to the insurance carriers and our financial partners. Developed an extranet reporting tool for external partners and Cognos reporting for executive managers and internal users. Real time key metrics measured to analyze and run the business on the day-to-day basis. Key metrics consisted of traffic, quote starts, quote completion, retrieve rate, conversion events, cost per sale (marketing cost + talk time), sales and commissions. Implemented and integrated a commercially packaged Agency Management System (Applied) into our enterprise database environment and developed a process to reconcile commission revenue with sold insurance policies. Evaluated ERP and CRM packages to identify internal business requirements and align those with vendor functionality.

TRAINING

Training Courses in project management, strategic planning, business area analysis, human factors design, database modeling, object-oriented analysis and design, and systems integration.

Clarity Budgeting and Time Tracking
SQL Server Design, Administration and Concepts
Software Project Management
Project Management and Control
Prototyping and Human Factors Design
Systems Design Workshop
Data Analysis Workshop
Database Design Workshop
Object-Oriented Analysis and Design
Client/Server Fundamentals
Certified PowerBuilder Developer
Fast Track to Sybase
Extended Relational Analysis and Design
Networking Technologies